-==破爛熊樂園傾情奉獻==-
本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
-=破爛熊字幕組=-
翻譯：考拉 Pi
校對：小敘
-=破爛熊字幕組=-
時間軸：睿睿
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
單身男人
1962年 11月30日 星期五
Friday, 30 November, 1962
起床有"想要"和"已經"之分
Waking up begins with saying "am" and "now".
珍妮弗 別讓我再說第二遍
Jennifer, I'm not gonna tell you again.
八個月以來 夢醒時分總是心痛無比
For the past eight months waking up has actually hurt.
我依然存活的殘酷意識 還在慢慢滲透
The cold realization that I'm still here slowly sets in.
我從未真正喜歡過醒來的感覺
I was never teribly fond of waking up.
我也無法像吉姆一樣
I was never one to jump out of bed
微笑著起來迎接新的一天
and greet the day with a smile like Jim was.
見他一大早就那麼開心 我甚至想過給他一拳
I used to want to punch him sometimes in the morning he was so happy.
我常跟他說
I always used to tell him that
只有愚人才會笑著迎接新一天
only fools greet the day with a smile...
...只有愚人才會對現實的一切置若惘然
...that only fools possibly escape the simple truth.
而現在 惘然都已經不復存在
That now isn't simply now.
就像一個冷酷的提示 日復一日
It's a cold reminder. One day later than yesterday.
年復一年
One year later than last year.
終有一天 它會來到你的身邊
And that sooner or later it will come.
他總是笑而不語 輕吻我的臉頰
He used to laugh at me and then give me kiss on the cheek.
每天早上 我要花上一段時間打扮成喬治
It takes time in the morning for me to become George.
我需要時間來適應
The time to adjust to
喬治的形象和他應有的表現
what is expected of George and how he is to behave.
待到我穿著得體 一切光彩煥然...
By the time I have dressed and put the final layer of polish...
...展現給人們一個不茍言笑
...on the now slightly stiff
卻栩栩如生的喬治的時候...
but quite perfect George...
...我就知道自己該扮演哪個角色了...
...I know fully what part I'm supposed to play
注視著鏡中自己的面龐
Looking in the mirror staring back at me
可以說不是一張面孔...
isn't so much as a face...
...而是困境折射出來的表情
...as the expression of a predicament.
熬過這混渾渾噩噩的一天吧
Just get through the goddamn day.
雖然有些戲劇化...
A bit melodramatic, I guess.
但說真的...
But then again...
...我的心已經受傷了
...my heart has been broken.
我覺得自己在慢慢下沉 慢慢被淹沒...
I feel as if I am sinking, drowning...
...無法呼吸
...can't breathe.
你不發表點見解嗎?
Aren't you going to say something?
開玩笑嗎?這簡直不可思議
Are you kidding? It's spectacular.
你要幹嘛?
What are you doing?
別這樣 別
Just stop it. Stop it.
我覺得你還沒準備好
I don't think that you're quite ready for
住在玻璃房子裡 (諺語 公佈於眾)
life in a glass house.
那就拉窗簾咯 老頭子
Drapes, old man.
是你一直都說我們是隱形的
You're the one who is always saying that we are invisible.
我不是這個意思
That's not exactly what I meant.
人生頭一回 我覺得未來如此渺遠
For the first time in my life I can't see my future.
每天都在懵懂的迷霧中悄然度過
Every day goes by in a haze.
而今天 我決定要過得迥然不同
But today I have decided will be different.
總算打來了 今天一直都在下雨
Finally. You know it's been raining here all day.
我就躲在屋子裡 等著你打電話來
I've been trapped in this house waiting for you to call.
抱歉 我是不是打錯了
I'm sorry, I must have the wrong number.
我要找喬治·福克納先生
I'm calling for Mr. George Falconer.
不好意思 我在等別人電話
I'm sorry, I was expecting someone else.
沒錯 您並...
Yes sir, you have indeed called the...
...沒有打錯 有什麼事情嗎?
...correct number. How may I help you?
我是哈羅德·阿克利
This is Harold Ackerley.
我是吉姆的表哥
I'm Jim's cousin.
哦 你好啊 晚上好 阿克利先生
Of course. Yes, good evening Mr. Ackerley.
恐怕我有些噩耗要告訴您
I'm afraid I'm calling with some bad news.
發生了一起車禍
There has been a car accident.
車禍?
An accident?
最近這裡一直下雪 道路比較滑
There has been a lot of snow here lately and the roads have been icy.
吉姆在進城的路上 剎車失靈了
On his way into town, Jim lost control of his car.
結果 一下子人就沒了
It was instantaneous apparently.
是昨天晚上發生的 但他父母不想通知您
It happened late yesterday, but his parents didn't want to call you.
我知道了
I see.
事實上 我現在也是背著他們打給你的
In fact, they don't that I'm calling you now.
因為我覺得應該讓你知道
But I thought that you should know.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我知道這對您打擊很大 我們都很悲痛
I know this must be quite a shock. It was for all of us.
是啊 沒錯
Yes, indeed.
要舉行葬禮嗎?      葬禮安排在後天
Will there be a service?        The day after tomorrow.
那我恐怕要放下電話...
Well, I suppose I should get off the phone...
...趕緊訂一班飛機
...and book a plane flight.
葬禮僅限家人
The service is just for family.
家人啊 當然
For family, of course.
那麼 謝謝你能通知我
Well, thank you for calling.
阿克利先生?      什麼事?
Mr. Ackerley?        Yes?
我想問問那兩條狗怎麼處理呢?
May I ask what happened to the dogs?
狗?
Dogs?
有一條跟著他的狗也死了 還有另外一條嗎?
There was a dog with him but he died. Was there another one?
嗯 還有一條小母狗
Yes, there was a small female.
這我就不清楚了 很抱歉
I don't know, I'm sorry.
我沒聽誰提起過另外那條狗
I haven't heard anyone mentioning another dog.
再次謝謝您能打來告訴我
Well, thank you for calling Mr. Ackerley.
再見 福克納先生
Goodbye, Mr. Falconer.
喂 夏莉
Hello, Charley.
你怎麼會知道是我?
How did you know it was me?
夏洛特 不會有別人在早晨8點之前打電話來的
Charlotte, nobody else calls me before eight in the morning.
不會是擾了你的清夢吧? 你聽起來不大高興
I didn't call too early, did I? You sound grumpy.
不 我只是有些頭痛
No, I have a headache.
我本來要給你打電話的
Listen, I was going to call you actually.
今晚的事我改主意還來得及嗎
Is it too late to change my mind about tonight.
來得及啊 怎麼來不及
No, of course not.
我只是一周都沒見你而已
I haven't seen you all week.
我都快想死你了      我知道 實在抱歉
I'm dying for a dose of you.        I know, I'm sorry.
那就這麼定了 今晚見
So great, I'll see you tonight.
我先掛了 上班要遲到了
I have to run. I'm late for the work.
等會兒到了學校再打給你
I'll call you later from school.
好的 晚上見
Alright, I see you then.
再見 小淘氣      再見 大哥哥
Bye, kiddo.        Bye, old man.
早上好 喬治先生
Good morning, Mr. George.
先生 您今天氣色不大好啊
Sir, you don't look so good today.
愛爾瓦 早安 我沒事 只是沒睡好而已
Good morning, Alva. No, I didn't sleep very well.
你今早忘記把麵包從冰箱裡拿出來了
You forgot to take the bread out of the freezer this morning.
那樣才能保鮮啊
It stays fresh that way.
不過今天早上有點兒太鮮了
It was a little too fresh this morning.
我桌上有幾張紙...
There are some papers laid out on my desk...
...放在那兒就好 不要動
...which need to stay there. Please don't move them.
抱歉我的鋼筆墨水染到床單上了
I'm afraid my pen leaked all over the bed.
沒關係的 先生
It's okay, sir.
愛爾瓦?      是的 先生?
Alva?        Yes, sir?
你真好 謝謝你
Thank you, you're a wonderful.
正如政府承諾的
This government, as promised,
他們會一如既往地對蘇軍在
has maintained the closest surveillance...
...古巴島上的軍事集結進行密切監視
...of the Soviet military buildup on the Island of Cuba.
過去幾周以來的確鑿證據...
Within the past week unmistakable evidence...
...讓我們有理由相信...
...has established the fact...
福克納教授?      怎麼了?
Professor Falconer?        Yes?
今早有個學生問我要了你的住址
There was a student here this morning asking for your address.
我的住址?
My address?
你給他了嗎?      是的 先生
Did you give it to him?        Yes, sir.
我給了
I did.
希望不會給您添麻煩
I hope that's okay.
之後我意識到也許不該給的 可他人真的很好
I realize that I probably shouldn't have but he was very nice.
所以我覺得他不會...
Before I knew it he...
你的髮型非常漂亮 很襯你
Your hair looks great up like that. I really fits suits you.
你總是那麼美艷動人...
You always look so beautiful...
...青春活潑...
...really fresh...
你笑起來很甜
You have such a lovely smile.
艾佩芝? (香水品牌)     先生?
Arpege?        Sir?
真的很漂亮
Really beautiful.
...一系列具有攻擊性的導彈基地
...that a series of offensive missile sites...
先生們 早上好      喬治 早上好
Good morning, Don.        Good morning, George.
早上好 喬治
Good morning, George.
早上好 格蘭特
Good morning, Grant.
你氣色不大好 怎麼了?
You look awful. What have you been doing?
格蘭特 看看你的周圍
Look around you, Grant.
大多數學生都只圖畢業後能去公司裡工作
Most of these students aspire to nothing more than corporate job...
...然後生一個
...and a desire to raise
喝著可樂 看著電視的小屁孩...
coke-drinking, TV-watching children...
...過不了幾年
...who as soon as they can speak
孩子就開始大唱廣告歌曲...
start chanting TV jingles...
...拿著錘子搞破壞了
...and smashing things with hammers.
喬治 你今天怎麼不大對勁
You're really scaring me today, George.
別跟我說 你和這些個學生相處很融洽
Don't tell me. You have easy time with these students.
我發現他們看我
I found them staring at me
像看一個喋喋不休的老先生一樣...
in a kind of bovine stupor...
...就好像我是用外語教書一般
...as if I were lecturing in a foreign language.
這也提醒了我們果然不是一個世界的人
Remind me why we shouldn't all just be annihilated.
你怎麼對什麼都一哂置之
You seem to think this is all a joke.
我們當前的世界 正瀰漫著核武器帶來的恐懼
We're living in a world where nuclear war is a real threat.
我不明白為什麼你毫不關心
I don't understand how that doesn't concern you.
你是認真的 對吧?
You're serious, aren't you?
是的 我很認真
Yes, I'm serious.
喬治 你到底讀沒讀
George did you even read
我給你的關於防空洞的文章?
the article I gave you on bomb shelters?
我們基本上談妥了 現在找了三個承包商...
Our is almost done. We had 3 contractors work on it...
...所以就不會有人知道這些
...so none of them know what we've got.
我會依照地形而建
I'm having the outside of it landscaped
這樣就神不知鬼不覺了
so no one will that it's there.
是嗎?
Really?
如果傳出去說你的防空洞比別人的好...
If word gets out that you've got a better shelter...
...那等到戰亂爆發 人們就一股腦地擠過來
...then everyone will try to get in when something happens.
所以呢?
So?
蘇聯的導彈扔過來
There will be no time for sentiment
就沒有時間留給你多愁善感了
when the Russians fire a missile at us.
格蘭特 倘若這世界沒有時間多愁善感...
If it's going to be a world with no time for sentiment Grant...
...那麼這也不會是我想要生活的世界
...the it's not a world that I want to live in.
"夏去夏來天鵝死"
After Many a Summer
(英國作家赫胥黎在1939年所寫小說)
Dies the Swan.
想必大家...
I think you've all...
...都讀過
...read the Huxley novel
我三周前佈置的這本赫胥黎的小說了吧
I assigned more than three weeks ago?
題目與作品有何關聯?
How does the title relate to our story?
蒙先生 請講
Yes, Mr. Mong.
並無關聯(赫胥黎引用"泰索尼斯"中的詩句)
It doesn't.
講述了一個富翁
It's about a rich guy
覺得自己已是垂暮 配不上那個女孩...
who's too afraid that he's too old for this girl...
...而他認為年輕的男人...
...and thinks that a young guy...
拉斯
Russ.
拉斯?
Russ?
請講 赫希先生
Yes, Mr. Hirsch.
先生 在第79頁 普羅普特先生說道...
Sir, on page 79, Mr. Propter says that...
...聖經中最愚蠢的章節就是
...the stupidest text in the Bible is
"他們無故地恨我"(約翰福音15:25)
they hated me without a cause.
這是為納粹對猶太人的憎惡開脫嗎?
Does that mean the Nazis were right to hate the Jews?
難道赫胥黎是一名反猶分子嗎?      不
Is Huxley an anti-Semite?        No.
不 赫胥黎先生並非反猶
No, Mr. Huxley is not an anti-Semite.
而且 納粹對猶太的民族仇恨是天大的錯誤
Of course, the Nazis were wrong to hate the Jews.
但他們對猶太人的恨並非無緣無故
But their hating the Jews was not without a cause.
只是這原因並不真實存在
It's just that the cause wasn't real.
憎恨的原因源於人們的臆想
The cause was imagined.
真正的原因是恐懼
The cause was fear.
咱們先暫且不要談論猶太的問題
Let's leave the Jews out o this just for a moment.
想想另一個少數派群體 那種...
Let's think of another minority. One that...
那種被人視而不見的少數派
One that can go unnoticed if it needs to.
其實這世上有著各種各樣的少數派
There are all sorts of minorities,
譬如金髮的人...
blondes for example...
...長著雀斑的人
...or people with freckles.
但是只有在少數派對多數派構成威脅時...
But a minority is only thought of as one...
...他們才被稱之為少數派
...when it constitutes some kind of threat to the majority.
是真實的 還是臆想的
A real threat or an imagined one.
這當中便產生了恐懼
And therein lies the fear.
倘若少數派不為人知被人忽略
If the minority is somehow invisible...
...那麼恐懼便無限放大
...and the fear is much greater.
恐懼的存在 導致少數派被迫害
That fear is why the minority is persecuted.
所以 你們看原因總是存在的
So, you see there always is a cause.
這原因便是恐懼
The cause is fear.
少數派其實就是普通人
Minorities are just people.
如我們一樣的普通人
People like us.
感覺好像把你們講糊塗了
I can see that I've lost you a bit.
這樣吧 咱們今天先不講赫胥黎了...
So tell you what? We're gonna forget about Mr. Huxley today...
...我們來探討一下恐懼
...and we're gonna talk about fear.
畢竟...恐懼才是我們真正的敵人
Fear, after all, is our real enemy.
恐懼正在吞噬著我們的世界
Fear is taking over our world.
恐懼被用來操控著我們的社會
Fear is being used as a tool of manipulation in our society.
這就是政客們玩弄的伎倆
It's how politicians peddle policy.
這也就是麥迪遜大道上總有人賣給我們
It's how Madison Avenue sells us
不需要的東西
things that we don't need.
仔細想想看
Think about it.
對被襲的恐懼
Fear of being attacked.
恐懼著某個暗處隱藏著共產主義者
Fear of that there are communists lurking around every corner.
恐懼著那些和我們生活習慣截然不同的...
Fear of that some little Caribbean country...
...中美洲國家會對我們
...that doesn't believe in our way of life
造成威脅(古巴危機)
poses a threat to us.
恐懼著黑人的文化將會統領全世界
Fear that black culture may take over the world.
擔心貓王的屁股哪天會晃掉下來
Fear of Elvis Presley's hips.
事實上 這個很有可能成為現實
Actually, maybe that one is a real fear.
恐懼著口臭會破壞我們的友誼
Fear that our bad breath might ruin our friendships.
恐懼著韶華逝去孑然一身
Fear of growing old and being alone.
恐懼著自己一無是處 無人問津
The of that we're useless and that no one cares what we have to say.
週末愉快
Have a good weekend.
先生! 我能跟你談談嗎?
Sir! May I talk to you for a minute?
為什麼你之前沒有這樣跟我們講過呢?
Why don't you always talk to us like that?
我怕你們不愛聽
I don't think it went over very well.
老師 我經常會有對週遭的恐懼
Man, fear of things gets to me all the time.
但你無法跟別人傾訴 否則會讓別人覺得你很傻
But you can't talk about it with anyone or you just sound like a fool.
連跟洛伊斯都不能傾訴嗎?
You can't even talk about it with Lois?
我覺得她什麼都不怕
I don't think she's afraid of anything.
每個人都有恐懼的東西 肯尼
Everyone's afraid of something, Kenny.
先生 那你怕什麼?
What are you afraid of, sir?
車
Cars.
你住在洛杉磯 怎麼能怕車呢?
How can you live in Los Angeles and be afraid of cars?
可能不能吧
Maybe you can't.
有時候 我內心的恐懼會讓我慌張無力
Sometimes my fear of things can almost paralyze me.
內心糾結緊張
It's like I get really panic stricken
生怕自己的感情會突然爆發
and I feel like I might explode or something.
我能問您個私人問題嗎 先生?
May I ask you a personal question, sir?
隨便
If you like.
你曾經嗨過嗎?
Do you ever get high?
你覺得我都多大歲數了?
How old do I look to you?
那您之前吸過毒嗎?
Have you ever taken any drugs?
當然 肯尼
Of course, Kenny.
譬如什麼?
Like what?
波特先生 我覺得
I don't feel I should be discussing
在校園討論這事情有點不合適吧
this with you on campus Mr. Potter.
這是我解壓的唯一方式
It's the only way I get by sometimes.
那您試過迷幻藥嗎?
Have you ever tried mescaline?
倒不是我的首選
Not my drug of choice.
有次吸完 我把半邊眉毛都刮掉了
I shaved off one of my eyebrows once on mescaline.
看上去不好看
Not a good look for me.
先生?      我對著鏡子
Sir?        I looked in the mirror.
吸完迷幻藥看鏡子是個錯誤至極的選擇
Big mistake if you're high on mescaline.
我感覺我的眉毛要把整個臉都吞噬了
I decided that my eyebrows were taking over my face.
所以我就刮掉了一半
Before I knew it, I had shaved one off.
我等眉毛長出來的時候
I wore a band-aid over my eye
被迫貼了六周的創可貼
for about six weeks while my brow grew back.
非常尷尬
Very embarrassing.
打那以後你就再沒碰過了?
You didn't take it again after that?
肯尼 你有聽我說話嗎?
Kenny, have you been listening to me?
我把眉毛都剃掉了啊
I shaved off my eyebrow.
我只是想要體驗一下 波特先生
I wanted an experience Mr. Potter,
又不是想當台上的小丑
not a career on stage.
先生 你什麼時候想要嗨一下的話 我這兒有貨
If you ever want to get high sir, I usually have some dope.
你還真是瘋了
You're really mad aren't you?
抱歉 先生
I'm sorry, sir.
或許這種交談讓你覺得不適
I guess you don't feel very comfortable talking like this.
此話怎講?
What makes you say that?
洛伊斯覺得你過於小心謹慎了 就像今早...
Lois thinks you're kind of cagey. Like this morning...
...你不動聲色地聽
...when you were listening to
我們高談闊論赫胥黎
all that crap we were talking about Huxley.
也不是所有人啊
Well, not all of you.
我記得你不是沒有開口嗎
I didn't notice you open your mouth once.
因為我在注視您
I was watching you.
你總是先讓我們發表見解
You let us ramble on and on
然後你再直言不諱地解釋
and then you straighten us out.
你卻從未主動告訴過我們你所認為的一切
But you never really tell us everything you know about something.
或許在一定程度上 你說得沒錯
Well, maybe that's true up to a point.
但這並不是我故意謹慎
It's not that I want to be cagey.
只是我真的無法將所有都放開談論
It's just that I can't really discuss things completely openly...
...尤其是在學校
...at school.
有人會誤會的
Someone would misunderstand.
就像我今天試過了 反響不是很好啊
I tried that today. It didn't really work out.
你是想來買什麼嗎 先生?
What was it you wanted to get, sir?
沒什麼 我是剛好要去院長辦公室
Nothing. I was on my way to the dean's office.
所以你走了這麼長的路就是為了跟我講話咯?
You mean you walked all the way down here just to talk to me?
是啊      那麼...
Why not?        Well...
先生 我覺得我應該好好答謝你才是了
I think you deserve something for that, sir.
看看吧 選一個 先生
Here sir, take your pick.
我送給您      謝謝
It's on me.        Thank you.
我還以為你會選藍色
I thought you'd probably pick blue.
為什麼是藍色?
Why blue?
藍色不是代表著靈性嗎?
Isn't blue supposed to be spiritual?
為什麼你覺得我會有靈性?
What makes you think I'm spiritual?
你呢? 紅色?
And you? Red?
紅色代表什麼?      那可太多了
What is red stand for?        A lot of things.
憤怒 慾望
Rage, lust.
開玩笑吧啊?
No kidding?
那麼 先生 我...
Well sir, I...
咱們再會啊
I guess I see you around.
喂?
Hello?
小淘氣 你在幹嘛呢啊?
What are you up to, kiddo?
正想要讀本書 你今天過得如何啊?
Just trying to finish up a book. How's your day going?
不錯
Fine.
我剛好要下班了
I was just leaving school
想問問你今晚需不需要帶點東西
and wanted to know if you needed anything for tonight.
謝謝 你可真貼心
Thanks, you're sweet.
不過我好像不缺什麼
But I think I'm all set.
你如果能...
Be a darling and...
...買點杜松子酒就更好了 唐桂來牌的吧
...pick up gin for me, Tangueray.
我喜歡瓶子的顏色
I love the color of the bottle.
你是喜歡瓶子裡邊的東西 你想要我幾點到?
You love what's in it. What time do you want me?
要是方便的話 7點鐘最好了
7 would be great if that's ok with you.
那好 到時見了
Perfect. I'll see you then.
到時見 再見了 喬
I'll see you then. Bye, Geo.
再見 小淘氣
Bye, kiddo.
很美
Beautiful.
波特先生 什麼事?
Yes, Mr. Potter?
您要去哪兒嗎 先生?
Are you going somewhere, sir?
人們開車不都是為了去哪兒嗎?
That is usually why people get into their cars.
不 我是說 你是要去度假或是什麼嗎?
No, I mean are you going on vacation or something?
什麼?
What?
我看您把辦公室都清理乾淨了?
I saw you cleaning out your office.
肯尼 你到底想要幹嘛?
What exactly is it that you want, Kenny?
我只是想說
I was just hoping that perhaps
找個時間 咱們可以喝一杯
we could get together for a drink or something sometime.
為什麼這麼說?
Why is that?
我也不清楚 先生
I don't know, sir.
可能我覺得你會喜歡這樣 而且...
Because I think you might like it. And...
...感覺您現在需要一個朋友的陪伴
...because you seem as though you could use a friend.
哦 是嗎?      是的 先生 您需要
Oh really?        Yes, sir. You do.
或許你說得對
They may be right.
下次找機會吧 我趕時間
It will have to be another time. I'm late.
不過謝謝你的誠摯邀請
But thank you for the invitation.
也謝謝你今早的那番話
And thank you for the talk earlier.
別再碰迷幻藥了
And stay away from the mescaline.
您好 福克納先生
Hello, Mr. Falconer.
嗯 你好嗎?      很好 先生
Hello. How are you today?        I'm fine, sir.
您需要拿保險箱出來嗎?      是的
Do you need to get into your box?        Yes, I do.
請跟我來
Follow me.
給您 先生
Here you are, sir.
麻煩請您在這裡簽名...
If you could please sign here...
謝謝      謝謝
Thank you.        Thank you.
跟我講講你那朋友 夏洛特
So explain your friend Charlotte to me.
你都想知道什麼?
What would you like to know?
我也不知道 聽起來你們關係很親密
I don't know. You seem very intimate I guess.
感覺你們之前曾經是戀人
Like you were once together or something.
你沒跟她睡過嗎?      睡過
You haven't slept with her, have you?        Yes.
然後呢?
And?
年輕的時候 一時衝動睡過幾次
A few times when we were young.
當然 這不可能對我毫無意義
I wouldn't say that it meant nothing to me...
...不過顯然這對夏莉的意義非比尋常
...but it certainly meant a great deal more to Charley.
那是很久之前在倫敦的事了
It was a long time ago in London.
我很愛夏莉
I love Charley.
我們是很好的朋友 就這樣
And We were very close friends but that's all.
這我倒不明白了
Well, I'm confused.
如果你和女人上床 那你為什麼跟我在一起?
If you sleep with women then why are you with me?
因為我會愛上男人
Because I fall in love with men.
因為我愛上了你
Because I fell in love with you.
再說了 誰沒在年輕時候 跟女人睡過啊?
Anyway, doesn't everyone sleep with women when they're young?
我沒有      你開玩笑
I haven't.        You're joking.
不 我沒開玩笑
No, I'm not.
感覺我好像對什麼都不感興趣
It was just never anything that interested me.
你還真是新潮啊
Well, you're awfully
(50-60年代青年人對世事不關心的態度)
modern aren't you?
你知道嗎 這也是我最初注意到你的一點...
You know, I think that was the first thing that I noticed about you...
...就是你的自信
...was how sure of yourself you were.
你這麼年輕怎會對一切都如此篤定?
How can you be so sure about everything at your age?
你覺得我真的瞭解自己嗎?
You think I'm sure of myself?
當然
Of course, you are.
我弄好了 謝謝你
I'm finished now. Thank you.
福克納先生?
Yes, Mr. Falconer?
還有什麼需要效勞的嗎?
Is there something else we can help you with today?
我找不到支票簿了 需要些現金
I can't find my check book and I need some cash.
真是運氣不佳啊 請稍等一會兒
Not my day I'm afraid. Excuse me a minute.
媽媽說濃眉的人太俗氣
Mommy says bushy eyebrows are pedestrian,
我覺得你的濃眉很漂亮
but I think yours are pretty.
你的也很漂亮啊
I think yours are pretty too.
為何你看上去這麼傷心?
Why do you look so sad?
你想要見見查爾斯·赫斯頓嗎?
Would you like to meet Charlton Heston?
賓虛
Ben Hur.
我說的是我的蝎子
He's our scorpion.
每晚餵它不同的食物 看著它把它們殺死
Every night we throw in something new to him and watch him kill it.
爸爸說就像是看角鬥一樣
Daddy says it's like the colosseum.
所以我哥哥湯姆就弄了些圓柱放進來
So my brother Tom put on all the columns in here.
他想當個佈景師
He wants to be a set designer.
它還沒有吃掉那只蜘蛛...
He hasn't eaten the spider yet...
...因為他還沒有消化完昨晚餵它的那只飛蛾
...cause he's still full from the moth we gave him last night.
爸爸說他想把你放進角鬥場去
Daddy says he wants to throw you in to the colosseum.
不是吧? 為什麼呢?
No kidding? Why?
他說你是穿拖鞋的(暗指他是同性戀)
He says you're light in your loafers...
可你根本沒穿拖鞋
...but you aren't even wearing loafers.
我覺得我哥哥湯姆也是個穿拖鞋的...
I think my brother Tom is light in his loafers too...
...可他穿的是凱茲牌(帆布鞋)
...but he wears Keds.
他讓我用雞蛋給頭髮做護理
He made me do a hair conditioning treatment on my hair with eggs.
看上去有光澤嗎?
Does it look shiny?
甜心 你怎麼在這裡打攪福克納先生呢?
Sweetheart, what are you doing bothering Mr. Falconer?
蘇珊 她沒有打擾到我 你好啊
She's not bothering me at all Susan. How are you?
喬治 很高興見到你
I'm glad to see you George.
喬治 我們今晚請了些人來喝酒...
George, we're having a few people over tonight for drinks...
...如果你能過來 大家一定很開心
...and would love to have you join us if you could.
謝謝你的好意 不過我另外有事了
Thank you. That's very kind of you but I have plans.
那就下次吧
Another time then.
珍妮弗 咱們別打擾福克納先生了
Jennifer, let's let Mr. Falconer get back to his banking.
喬治 再見
Goodbye, George.
再見 蘇珊 再見 珍妮弗
Bye, Susan. Bye, Jennifer.
先生 需要點什麼嗎?
May I help you, sir?
我想買這把槍用的子彈 謝謝
I'd like to buy some bullets for this gun, please.
嗯 先生 這把槍可是有年頭了啊
Yes, sir. This is a really old gun, sir.
我們正在搞促銷 買二贈送一把手槍
We have a two for one sale on handguns at the moment.
要不要買一把送給女士呢?
Perhaps one for the little lady?
不必了 我只要子彈就好了
No thank you. Just the bullets, please.
給您 還需要點什麼嗎?
Here you go. Anything else?
不用了 謝謝
No, thank you.
一共2塊29分 先生
That would be $2.29, sir.
謝謝
Thank you.
抱歉 但願她沒衝你亂吠吧
I'm sorry. I hope she didn't growl at you.
她有時會有些失控 所以我把她放在車裡
She goes a little crazy sometimes when I have to leave her in the car.
她很漂亮 叫什麼名字?
She's perfect. What's her name?
印蒂雅
India.
過去
Let's go there.
來 小可愛
You little baby.
我之前也養過獵狐犬 這種狗不怎麼常見
I used to have smooth fox terriers. You don't see them very often.
這狗聞起來像是奶油吐司
The very smell of buttered toast.
她還是個小狗 對吧?
She's still a puppy isn't she?
那麼
Well.
祝您晚上愉快     你也是
Have a nice evening.        You too.
晚安 印蒂雅
Good night, India.
真不好意思      沒關係的
I'm sorry about that.        No, It's ok.
是我的錯 我再給你買包煙
It's my fault. I'll get you another pack.
沒關係的
It's ok. Don't worry.
不 不 我還是買吧
No, no I insist.
謝謝
Thank you.
謝謝 抱歉在門口打爛了瓶子
I'm sorry about the broken glass.
給你      謝謝了 夥計
Here you go.        Thanks man.
要來一根嗎?
You want one?
不 謝謝
No, thanks.
算了 來一根又有何妨嘛
Actually, yes. Why not?
謝謝
Thank you.
卡洛斯      你說什麼?
Carlos.        What did you say?
卡洛斯 你問我的名字嘛
Carlos. You asked me my name.
你沒事吧
Are you okay?
哦 沒事
Yeah.
嗯 抱歉
Yeah, I'm sorry.
(西語)你真是棱角分明
You're really something.
臉龐猶如雕塑
You have an incredible face.
好好利用 這是上天的恩賜
Enjoy that. It's a great gift.
你的西班牙語很不錯
Your Spanish is perfect.
謝謝
Thank you.
你應該更加好好珍惜你的外表
I should have used it more.
其實...
Well...
現在也不算晚
It's not too late.
你要幹嘛?
What are you doing?
不是要去什麼地方嗎?
Aren't we going somewhere?
不 不過 謝謝你
No. But, thanks.
是煙霧
You know, it's the smog
造就了夕陽的餘暉(洛杉磯的光化學煙霧)
that makes it that color.
我從未見過這樣的天空
I've never seen a sky like this before.
有時候 醜陋也有自己獨特之美
Sometimes awful things have their own kind of beauty.
我能再來一根嗎?
Could I have another cigarette?
當然
Sure.
你確定不想去兜兜風嗎?      我確定
Are sure that you don't want to go for a drive?        I'm sure.
你從哪兒來?      馬德里
Where are you from?        Madrid.
馬德里? 你是怎麼來這裡的
Madrid? How did you get here?
說來話長
It's a long story.
我在工作的旅店認識了一個洛杉磯來的小伙子...
I met a guy from LA at the hotel where I worked...
...他告訴我
...who told me
我可以跟他住 他可以給我找份工作
I could live with him and that he could get me an agent.
但他沒想過 我有西班牙口音
But he never realized that I have a Spanish accent.
我喜歡你的口音 你說起來非常動聽
I like your accent. You speak very well.
你怎麼學的英語?
How did you learn English?
我小時候 媽媽有個美國男友
My mom had an American boyfriend when I was little.
你媽媽現在在馬德里嗎?
Is your mother in Madrid?
嗯 是的 她是理髮師
Yes, she is. She cuts hair.
她在我走之前 為我剪了頭髮
She cut my hair before I left.
你喜歡這髮型嗎?
Do you like it?
我覺得 我看起來像詹姆斯·迪恩
I thought it made me look like James Dean.
你比詹姆斯·迪恩還好看
You are better than James Dean.
真的?
Really?
承蒙誇獎
Thanks.
從沒有人跟我搭訕卻對我毫無企圖
No one has ever picked me up and not wanted something.
我覺得是你找我搭訕的吧
I think you picked me up.
今天對我來說是相對煩惱的一天
This is kind of a serious day for me.
說說看 像你這樣的人怎會有煩惱?
Come on. What could be so serious for a guy like you?
我是想要忘卻一位舊愛
I'm just trying to get over an old love I guess.
我媽媽說 愛人就像是公共汽車
My mother says that lovers are like buses.
只要你耐心等待 下一輛自然會來
You just have to wait a little while and another one comes along.
我得走了
I have to go.
你是個不錯的人
You're a nice guy.
希望你能夠找到...
I hope you find...
...和你一樣的人
...someone like you.
謝謝
Thanks.
我先走了
I'm going away.
輪到你去換了
It's your turn to change it.
才不要 是輪到你了
Yeah, I'm not changing it. It's your turn.
再說了 我放什麼你都不喜歡的
Besides, you never like what I put on anyway.
我付你五塊錢去換 我太老了 站不起來
I'll give you five dollars if you change it. I'm too old to get up.
你只有在能佔便宜的時候才倚老賣老
You're only old when it's convenient for you to be old.
你在讀什麼呀
What are you reading anyway?
變形記 卡夫卡著
Metamorphosis
老天 又是那些無病呻吟的狗屎
Oh God. Not that depressing crap again.
上課用的
It's for my class.
你讀的又是什麼高級小說啊
What highbrow work of fiction might you be reading?
蒂凡尼的早餐 卡波特著
Breakfast at Tiffany's
少瞧不起人
Don't be so smug.
它的日子多好
Man, what a life he has.
真叫人羨慕     為什麼
Don't you just envy him?        Why?
因為誰的屁股它都可以湊上去?
Because he can sniff anyone's arse he wants?
真高雅
Nice.
是因為它隨心所欲 就像昨天...
No, because he just does what he wants. Like yesterday...
...我站在院子前 蘇珊過來聊天
...I was standing in the front yard and Susan came over to talk.
她家那個小少爺克裡斯托弗...
And that little brat of hers Christopher came...
...跑來耀武揚威地搖他那把破槍
...running over waving that damned gun of his around.
咱們家小狗就走過去 抬起腿...
And our little dog walked right up, hiked his leg...
...尿透了他的球鞋
...and peed all over Christopher's new tennis shoes.
老實說是尿透了他全身
All over Christopher actually.
當然 我得裝作一副很生氣的模樣
And of course, I had to act like I was upset
它太神了 你真該看看
It was so perfectly executed you should have seen it.
這隻小可憐過去被那些小孩折磨了這麼多年
After all the times those kids have tortured that poor dog.
你真該學學它們 它們...
I mean, you should take a lesson from him. They don't...
它們不會徹夜不眠地思慮
They don't stay up all night worrying.
它們找出了
They figured out
一套操控我們的辦法
how to get the two of us to do exactly what they want.
認真想想 它倆基本就是
They are basically
兩隻深沉的米蟲嘛
very sophisticated little parasites when you think about it.
最愚蠢的物種總是最快樂的
Well, the dumbest creatures are the happiest.
以你媽為例
Just look at your mother.
它真是今朝有酒今朝醉
He's really just living the moment.
就好比現在
It's like now.
還有什麼比跟你窩在一起更好的呢
What could be better than being tucked up here with you?
就算要我立刻死掉 也無所謂了
If I died right now it would be OK.
我很有所謂
Well, it wouldn't be OK with me
所以趕緊閉嘴去換唱片吧
so why don't you shut up and go change the record.
這答案不錯
Good answer.
你不介意的話 我下周想把它們一起
You know what? I was thinking about taking them up...
...帶上去丹佛
...to Denver with me next week if it's okay with you.
我媽愛死它們了
It's my mom. She loves them.
估計是因為本是同根生吧
Probably that recognition of a similar mind.
您待著吧 老頭
You stay there, old man.
請系溫莎結
Tie in a windsor.
我沒忘松子酒的事兒 十分鐘後見
No, I did not forget the gin. I'll see you in ten minutes.
克裡斯托弗 你說我幹掉你怎麼樣
Christopher, would you like it if I killed you?
不知道
I don't know.
你再這樣下去 就會知道了
If you keep this up we're going to find out.
所以趕緊回家 別射人了
So, why don't you go home and stop shooting people?
見到你真好
I'm so happy to see you.
快進來
Come on in.
好香啊 我好餓 路易斯呢
It smells wonderful. I'm very hungry. Where is Lois?
我放了她一晚假 今晚我親自下廚
I gave her the night off. I'm cooking myself.
是嘛?      我試著做了點新菜品
You are?        Yes, I'm trying something new.
夏莉寶貝 你下廚房本身已經夠"新鮮"的
Charley darling, "you cooking' is new.
少油嘴滑舌
Don't be smart.
今晚我心情好 我要盡情歡樂
I'm in a good mood tonight. I'm going to be fun.
我已經許下新年決心了
I've already made two New Year's resolutions.
決心一 再也不提我的雞巴前夫...
Resolution one: No more talk that of awful ex-husbands...
和沒良心的孩子了
..and children who don't give a damn.
還有呢      還有什麼
And the other one?        One what?
決心
Resolution.
決心二
Resolution two:
多喝 多抽 去他媽的 來
More smoking and more drinking and screw it all! So come on...
...給我調杯酒
...mix me up a drink.
我要來杯松子酒加湯力水
I'll have a gin and tonic, please.
瞧好了吧寶貝兒      馬上來
And watch out baby!        Coming up.
你今晚能來真是太體貼了
It was sweet of you to come tonight.
這跟體貼無關
Sweet had nothing to do with it.
我也需要見你      少來了
I needed to see you.      Oh,Geo. Come off it.
每次你體貼別人時總是不好意思承認
Whenever you do something sweet you're too ashamed to admit it.
來敬我們的新年前決心
Here is to our early New Year's resolutions.
乾杯
Cheers.
你的決心是什麼
What are your resolutions by the way?
完全 徹底 永遠地遺忘過去
To let go of the past completely, entirely, and forever.
點根兒煙 好嗎
Light me up, will you?
親愛的 你氣色不對啊
Darling, you don't look well.
還記得你去年的那場心臟病嗎
Do you remember that little heart attack you had last year?
那算不上心臟病
It wasn't a heart attack.
不管那是什麼 親愛的...
Well whatever it was darling...
...你現在可一點都不性感
...you don't look so hot.
我挺好 從沒感覺這麼好過
I'm fine. I never felt better.
就是有點累 已經好久沒睡...
I'm a little tired. I haven't been sleeping...
這很正常 老喬
Geo, it's normal.
你和吉姆在一起16年了
You were with Jim for 16 years.
我至今都日夜思念理查呢
I think about Richard every day.
孤單是一種病啊
It's hard being alone.
至少你還有自己的工作和生活
At least you have a job and a life.
去嘗嘗晚餐 如何
Let's have a bit of dinner shall we?
我可花了老大功夫來做呢
Because I've worked so very hard.
你說什麼啊
What are you talking about?
真的 現在沒有"老"這個說法了
Seriously, there no such thing as old anymore.
我一個學生有一天管我叫"老年市民"
The other day one of my students has called me a senior citizen.
我不在乎"老"的存在與否...
I wouldn't mind if old didn't exist...
...但估計"老年"我也談不上喜歡吧
...but I'm not sure senior is what I'm aiming for either.
一切都變得那麼寡然無味
It's all becoming so bland.
這可不是我來美國的原因
It's not why I came to America.
彷彿一切文化和禮儀都一夕之間分崩離析了
It's like a complete breakdown of culture and manners.
那些年輕人根本不懂禮儀
The young ones have no manners.
有一天在洗車店
The other day at the car wash
一個年輕人上下打量我一番...
a young man looked me up and down...
...然後居然問我的金髮是不是天生的
...and actually asked me if I was a natural blonde.
你怎麼說      我盯著他的眼睛...
What did you say?        I looked him straight in the eye...
...說"這麼說吧 我倒立起來的話...
...and said: "Let's just say if I stood on my head...
...就是個天生的口氣清新的黑髮美女了"
...I would be a natural brunette with lovely breath.
不會吧      真的
You didn't!        I did!
有趣的事他立馬就相信了
And the amusing thing was that it went right over his head!
你早在倫敦的時候就是個刀子嘴
You know, you had a mouth on you even back in London.
你還記得那個拿飲料砸你的女同志嗎...
Do you remember that old lesbian who threw her drink over your head...
...就因為你問人家的洞洞夠不夠用
...because you asked her if she was hung like a donut.
老喬
Geo.
我們兩 隨時都能回倫敦去啊
We could always go back to London. The two of us.
免了 多謝      你知道你懷念倫敦的
No, thanks.        You know you miss it.
偶爾為之
I miss it sometimes.
吉姆活著的話或許還有可能
Maybe if Jim had lived.
他喜歡呆在英國
He loved being in England.
我們上次回去的時候他就想留下
He asked us to stay the last time we were there.
你認真考慮過搬回去的事嗎
Do you really think you would have moved?
不知道 這事說起來都覺得很傻 只是個幻想
I don't know. It's silly to even talk about it. It was only a fantasy.
這是什麼
What's this?
我媽的婚戒
It's my mother's wedding ring.
我清理抽屜時找到的
I found it a drawer when I was cleaning out.
夏莉寶貝 我倆都需要再來一杯
Charley my dear, you and I are both in need of another drink.
等等 等等
Wait! Wait, wait!
我超愛這首
I love this!
你個瘋女人      來嘛 老傢伙
You're insane!        Come on, old man!
別動
Don't move.
謝謝
Thank you.
點煙老手了啊      我一直想這麼點煙
Very smooth cigarette move.        I've always wanted to do that.
你都不抽煙了
You don't even smoke.
有16年沒抽了 吉姆不喜歡
Well, not for the last sixteen years. Jim hated it.
現在何樂不為呢 也氣不死他了
What's to stop me now? It's not as if he's gonna to kill me.
這樣和你躺在這兒 真好
This is so nice, lying here with you.
你會不會懷念
Don't you ever miss this?
我們本可以發展成為什麼樣的關係呢?
What we could have been to each other?
真正的感情 結婚生子的感情
Having a real relationship and kids?
我有吉姆      我指真正的感情
I had Jim.        I know, but I mean a real relationship.
老喬 老實說
Geo, let's be honest,
你和吉姆很美妙但...
what you and Jim had together was wonderful but...
...那也只是別的事的替代品吧
...wasn't it really just a substitute for something else?
這真是你這些年來的想法嗎
Is that really what you think after all of these years?
你覺得吉姆於我來說只是個真愛的替代品?
You think Jim was just some kind of substitute for real love?
吉姆不是什麼的替代品
Jim was not a substitute for anything.
你明白嗎
Do you understand?
任何人都不可能...
There is no substitute for Jim...
...替代他
...anywhere!
再說 你跟理查的關係又多真摯了嗎
And by the way, what is so real about your relationship with Richard?
他九年後就離開你了
He left you after nine years!
吉姆和我在一起整整16年
Jim and I were together for sixteen years!
他要是沒死我們還會在一起
And if he hadn't died we would still be together!
這還他媽不夠真實嗎
What the hell is not real about that?
對不起 對不起 對不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
我知道你們有多相愛
I know how much the two of you loved each other.
我可能只是嫉妒我倆不能那樣相愛吧
I suppose I'm just jealous that you and I never had that kind of love.
老實說我從沒跟任何人那樣相愛過
Actually, I've never had that kind of love with anybody.
理查除了喜歡我的外表...
I don't think Richard ever loved me...
...估計從沒愛過我吧
...except for the way I looked.
還有克雷
And Clay...
我也不知道 你含辛茹苦地養大孩子...
I don't know. You raise a child and love it...
...他們羽翼豐滿了就離開你
...and then when they are old enough they just leave.
夏莉 其實你的生活沒什麼問題
Charley, there is nothing wrong with your life.
但你就是喜歡自憐自艾
You just like feeling sorry for yourself.
這是你的一大愛好
It's one of your great pleasures.
你不一樣嗎
And it's not one of yours?
你跟我一樣可悲
You're as pathetic as I am.
自憐自艾可不是我的最大愛好
Feeling sorry for myself is definitely not one of my great pleasures.
也不是我的
Well, it's not one of mine either.
我一點都不喜歡自憐自艾
I don't like feeling sorry for myself one bit.
我一直都想留住理查...
I tried to hold onto Richard for so long...
...即便除了我全世界都知道沒希望了
...even when it was obvious to everyone but me that it was over.
現在克雷也長大了
And now Clay is grown up.
我在這兒幹嘛啊老喬 告訴我啊
I mean, what am I doing here Geo? Tell me, what?
你有這麼多朋友 你沒事的
You have plenty of friends. You'll be fine.
我是有朋友 但他們都不需要我啊
Yes, I have friends. But none of them need me.
我也有你
And yes I have you
你要個該死的同志的話我們就能皆大歡喜了
and if you weren't such a goddamn poof we could have all been happy!
我現在有你 也是因為你失去了吉姆
I only have you now because you lost Jim.
但很快你又會有別人的
Soon I'll lose you to someone else.
這對女人來說沒那麼容易的
It's not as easy for a woman.
所有事我都竭盡了全力...
I've done everything the way I was supposed to and...
...而現在身邊只剩下的 是一瓶松子酒
...all I have to keep me company is a bottle of gin.
你或許也該找個洞洞來下酒
Maybe you should try donuts with your gin.
去你的
Screw you.
夏洛特 你太能演了
Charlotte, you are dramatic.
我差點就當真了
I swear you really almost had me.
一小滴眼淚都要從我眼角邊落下了
A tiny tear was beginning to form in the corner of my eye.
別這樣了
Now stop it.
你仍舊美得讓人窒息啊
You are still breathtakingly beautiful.
只要你肯打起精神從床上爬下來...
When you can be bothered to get up and out of bed...
...不要再事事都怨聲連連
...and you stop whimpering about everything for five minutes.
去倫敦吧 改變你的生活
Go to London. Change your life.
做女人做得不開心 就別婆婆媽媽的了
If you're not happy being a woman then stop acting like one.
你總有一切問題的答案
You have all the answers.
我沒什麼答案
No, I don't have any to mention.
你要真這麼聰明 何不改變自己的生活
If you're so smart why don't you have something new in your life?
接受斯坦福大學的職位
Take that position at Stanford.
你總是抱怨那所破學校
You complain about that little school
但你其實想去哪都行的
but you could go anywhere you want.
我覺得自己的付出還是有回報的
I think what I've done has been worthwhile.
抱歉 抱歉
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
我不該這麼說的
I shouldn't have said that.
儘管很厭惡 但我想我還是會回倫敦的
As much as I dread it, I think I will go back to London.
幹嘛要厭惡?
Why do you dread it?
我在倫敦時既年輕又新鮮
When I lived in London last I was young.
世界都在我腳下
I was fresh, I was everything.
來美國就像個夢想 像是蛋糕上的糖霜
Coming to America was such a dream, it was the icing on the cake.
回家則是挫敗
Going home is defeat.
沒有什麼事如我所願的
None of it really worked out the way I'd planned.
大多數事情都是不隨人願的
Most things don't work out the way people plan.
你一直活在過去
You're just living in the past.
你得開始考慮未來了
You need to start thinking about your future.
活在過去就是我的未來
Living in the past is my future.
你就不必如此 你是個男人
It doesn't have to be yours. You're a man.
而且今晚你是個悶蛋男人
And you're a bore tonight.
我們就不能再自怨自艾一小會兒嗎
Can't we just feel sorry for ourselves a little bit longer?
再喝一杯吧
Let's have another drink.
算了 我得走了
I don't think so. I have to go.
來陪我出去      求你啦
Come on. Walk me out.        Please, please!
好了 我得走了      不行 這麼好玩的
Come on, I have to!        No, this was such fun! No.
我什麼時候能再見你?
When will I see you again?
你不是要去英國嗎      我絕對不會去的
Aren't you going to England?        I'll never do that!
太花功夫了
It's far too much effort.
再說
Besides,
吉姆也不希望我把你一個人留在洛杉磯
I don't think Jim would want me to leave you here in LA all alone.
別擔心我
Don't worry about me. I'll be fine.
我有一切問題的答案 不是嗎
I've got all the answers. Remember?
你這週末幹嘛
What are you doing this weekend?
很安靜地待著吧
I think I might just be very quiet.
你從沒對我認真過 對吧 喬治
You never really did take me seriously, did you George?
我試過了 夏莉 記得嗎 很早以前
I tried to Charley. Remember? A long time ago.
但沒有結果 不是嗎
It didn't really work out, did it?
別 夏莉
No, Charley.
晚安
Sleep tight.
帕特裡克 來杯啤酒 一包煙
Patrick, a beer and a packet of Lucky Strike, please.
勞駕
Excuse me.
裡頭太熱了
It's too hot in there.
沒錯
Yes, it is.
來根兒煙?      謝了 我不抽煙
Would you like a cigarette?        No thanks, I don't smoke.
這兒人真多      週六晚上嘛
This place is really crowded.        Well, it is Saturday night.
通常人都很多的
It's usually as bad as this.
大家基本都是在這裡搭個人
People normally just stop by and pick someone up
去海邊折騰
and then head on down the beach.
嗯 這兒挺狂野的
Yeah. It's pretty wild out there.
很奇怪警察還沒來查
I'm surprised the cops don't break it up.
這裡總是這樣的嗎      戰後開始
Is it always like that?        Since the war ended.
其實挺棒的 像是邪教聚會
It's pretty great actually. It's kind of pagan.
我叫吉姆      我是喬治
I'm Jim.        I'm George.
幸會 吉姆
Pleased to meet you Jim.
抱歉 我原本是來找朋友的 但我找不著了
I'm sorry, I'm supposed to meet some friends but I can't find them.
我只是出門轉轉
I just needed to get out of the house
但沒禁受住冰啤的誘惑
but the lure of a cold beer got to me.
你住在附近?
Do you live hereby?
在峽谷那兒
Canyon.
住了多久了      38年開始
For how long?        Since 38.
你哪兒來的?      科羅拉多
Where are you from?        Colorado.
我很喜歡這裡 離海灘很近·
I really like it here. It's close to beach.
等我退伍後 我估計就會留在這兒了
I think I might stay after I'm discharged.
或許我也有點邪教氣息吧
I don't know, maybe I'm a bit of a pagan.
你先請      不
After you.        No.
抱歉
Sorry.
你好啊      嗨
Well, hello.        Hi.
可以給我買杯酒嗎
Do you buy me a drink?
我有伴了
I think I'm taken.
太可惜了 太可惜了
Too bad, too bad.
還想再來一杯嗎
Do you want another beer?
帕特裡克 打包威士忌和一包煙
Patrick, a bottle of scotch and a pack of Lucky Strikes to go, please?
帕特裡克 不要了
Patrick, cancel that.
你好啊 波特先生
Well, hello Mr. Potter.
你好 先生
Hello, sir.
我們喝什麼?      蘇格蘭威士忌
What are we drinking?        Scotch.
好吧
Okay.
我常來這兒
I come here all the time.
我就住在附近 你知道的
I live just around the corner, but then you knew that.
住在坎弗樹路上
On Camphor Tree Lane.
你還帶在身上
You're still carrying that around.
人必須對生活賜予的小禮物報以感恩
One must always appreciate life's little gifts.
你在這兒幹嘛呢
So, what are you doing here?
出來踩踩單車而已      僅此而已?
Just out for a ride on my bike.        Is that all?
不知道啊
I don't know.
你是在找我嗎
Were you looking for me?
可能吧 我不知道
Maybe. I don't know.
我覺得自己腦袋塞滿了東西
I feel like my head's stopped up with stuff.
什麼東西
What kind of stuff?
譬如您今天在課上說的東西
Like, the stuff you were talking about today in class.
那些完全無關緊要
That is definitely not important.
不 很重要的 您的課很棒
No, it is important. Your class is great.
但我們好像總是在談論著過去
But somehow we always seem to get stuck talking about the past.
我不關心過去
The past just doesn't matter to me.
那當下呢      我等不及讓當下成為過去
The present?        I can't wait for the present to be over.
當下太拖拉了
It's a total drag.
但今晚是個例外
Well, tonight is the exception.
怎麼?
What?
今晚 好! 當下 壞!
Tonight, yes! The present, no!
敬今晚
Let's drink to tonight.
Tonight.
如果過去無關緊要 當下又十分拖拉
So if the past doesn't matter and the present is a total drag.
那麼未來呢
What about the future?
什麼未來 我們或許就要被古巴炸飛了
What future? Cuba might just blow us up.
未來就是死亡啊
Death is the future.
抱歉 我不是故意要說得這麼消極的
I'm sorry. I don't mean to be depressing.
不消極 不消極 很真實
It's not depressing. It's not depressing, it's true.
這或許不是近期的將來 但卻是我們共同的歸宿
It may not be your immediate future but it's what we all share.
死亡就是未來
Death is the future.
我想 你是對的
You're right, I guess.
當人無法再當下獲得快樂時...
If one is not enjoying one's present there isn't a great deal to...
...未來的快樂就更是未知的了
...suggest that the future should be any better.
嗯 我過去想過這個
Yeah, I've thought that before.
但問題是 你永遠無法預知
But the thing is you just never know.
譬如今晚
Look at tonight.
老實說...
Actually...
...我時常感覺孤單
...I feel really alone most of the time.
是嗎      嗯
You do?        Yeah.
我總是有這種感覺
I've always felt this way.
我們孤單一人出世 孤單一人離去
I mean we're born alone, we die alone.
在這世上
And while we're here
我們又被徹底完全地封印在這身體裡
we are absolutely, completely sealed in our own bodies.
真夠怪的
Really weird.
每每想到這個都會很害怕
Kinda freaks me out to think about it.
我們只能通過自己扭曲的角度
We can only experience the outside world
來體驗世界
through our own slanted perception of it.
誰知道你的真是面目呢
Who knows what you're really like?
我看見的只是我認為的你的樣子
I just see what I think you're like.
我完全表裡如一的
I'm exactly what I appear to be.
只要你走近了看
If you look closely.
你知道嗎 人生最有價值的...
You know the only thing that has made the whole thing worthwhile...
幾個瞬間
...has been those...
就是當我
...few times
真正和他人交心的時刻
that I've been able to really, truly connect with another human being.
我對您有一種預感 先生
I had a hunch about you, sir.
是嗎      對
You did?        Yes, sir.
我感覺您一定是個浪漫主義者
I had a hunch you might be a real romantic.
人人都說...
You know, everyone keeps telling you that...
...人老了以後講積累許多經驗
...when you're older, that you'll have all this experience.
彷彿那是件很好的東西
Like it's some great thing.
這都是扯淡
That's a load of shit.
我覺得自己是越來越愚蠢了
I think I've actually just gotten sillier and sillier.
是嗎      絕對的
Really?        Absolutely.
所以 所有的經驗都是無用的
So, all your experience is useless.
倒也不是
No, I wouldn't say that.
如我們的朋友赫胥黎先生所說
As our friend Mr. Huxley says:
經驗不是人遇見的事
Experience is not what happens to a man.
而是人對所遇見事物的反應
It is what a man does with what happens to him.
去游泳吧      好啊
Let's go swimming.        Okay.
怎麼      那是個測試
What?        It was a test.
我以為你說變傻的事是在虛張聲勢...
I thought you were bluffing about being silly so...
...所以我想建議你
...I said to myself I'll suggest
做一件絕對出格的事兒
doing something completely outrageous.
如果你反對 甚至有一絲猶豫
And if he resists, if he even hesitates
那你就是滿口胡言
then I know he's full of shit.
看來我不是了 你是嗎
Well, I wasn't. Were you?
當然不是
Hell, no!
來吧先生 我幫你下去
Come on sir. I'll help you down.
走
Let's go.
來啊先生
Come on, sir.
先生?
Sir?
差不多了 先生
That's enough for now, sir.
我沒事      但我冷了 走吧
I'm fine.        I'm cold. Come on.
可以去您家嗎 先生
Can we go back to your place, sir?
當然 不然去哪
Of course. Where else?
不然去哪      你傻啊
Where else.        Are you out of your mind?
怎麼了      你不能就這樣回家吧
What's the matter?        You can't get home like that!
我們是隱形的 您不知道嗎
We're invisible, don't you know that?
先生 他們以後不能讓您單獨行事
You know sir, they ought not to let you out on your own.
你絕對是個惹麻煩的人
You're liable to get into real trouble.
是我的強項
I excel at it.
您額頭出血了
Your forehead is bleeding.
你想洗澡的話 浴室就在走廊盡頭
The bathroom is just down the hall if you would like to take a shower.
您不洗個澡嗎 先生
Aren't you taking a shower too, sir?
我沒事 我們英國人就愛又濕又冷
I'm fine. I'm English. We like to be cold and wet.
我想我們得先處理一下傷口 先生
First, I think that we need to take care of that cut, sir.
您有創可貼嗎
Do you have any band-aids?
您要去野營嗎 先生      我沒事 真的
Going camping, sir?        I'm fine, really.
呆在這兒 我馬上回來
Stay there. I'll be right back.
坐起來
Sit up.
仰頭
Tilt your head back.
先生 這回您恐怕不能以迷幻藥...
Well sir, I'm afraid this time you don't have...
...作為您貼創可貼的原因了
...the excuse of mescaline to explain your band-aid.
你該把濕衣服脫下來
I think we should get you out of those wet clothes.
遵命
Yes, sir.
不會冷吧      我挺好
You're not too cold?        I'm great.
想來一杯嗎      啤酒吧 如果您有的話
Would you like a drink?        A beer, sir. If you have one.
恐怕我就只有這個了
I'm afraid that's all we have.
兩杯啤酒 馬上就來
Two beers coming up.
您一個人住在這裡嗎 先生
You live here all by yourself, sir?
現在是了
I do now.
曾經是和一個朋友同住 他是個建築師
I used to share this place with a friend. He was an architect.
我們這年紀的人做夢都想要有這房子的設施啊
Man, guys my age dream about the kind of setup you've got here.
夫復何求啊
I mean, what more can you want?
可以獨自生活 來去自如
You get to be left alone and come and go as you please.
這就是你的理想生活嗎
Is that's your idea of the perfect life?
怎麼 先生 您不相信嗎
What's the matter, sir? Don't you believe me?
如果你這麼熱愛獨自一人的生活...
If you're so keen on the idea living by yourself...
...洛伊斯對你來說又是什麼呢
...where does Lois fit into this plan?
洛伊斯?這關她什麼事?
Lois? What's she got to do with anything?
我感覺你倆是一對的
I got the impression that you and she were together.
談不上 她挺酷的...
Not really. She is kind of cool and...
...我們是好朋友但...
...we're good friends but...
您真正想問的是我倆有沒有上過床吧
I think what you really want to ask me is if we sleep together.
上過嗎      上過 有一次
And do you?        We did. Once.
怎麼只有一次
Why only once?
我沒說"只有一次" 是"有一次"
I didn't say only once, I said once.
拜託 我現在最不想說的就洛伊斯了
Come on, the last thing I want to talk about right now is Lois.
現在幾點了
What time is it?
我的表似乎停了
My watch seems to have stopped.
你想讓我走了嗎
Do you want me to go?
開玩笑 再去拿兩杯啤酒來
You must be kidding. Go, get us another beer.
這是命令嗎 先生
Is that an order, sir?
當然
You're damn right it is.
可悲啊
Pathetic.
您說什麼了嗎 先生
Did you say something, sir?
你為什麼來這兒
Why are you here?
你為什麼去辦公室 向秘書要我的地址
Why did you get to the office and ask secretary for my address?
我只想在學校以外的地方見到您
I just wanted to see you someplace other than school.
為什麼
Why?
有時我覺得自己瘋了
Sometimes I think I'm crazy
因為我看到的世界和眾人不同
cause I see things so differently than everyone else.
我感覺可以向您傾訴
I feel like I can talk to you.
老實說先生 我今天很擔心您
To be honest sir, I was also worried about you today.
我嗎
Me?
有什麼好擔心的
What's to be worried about?
我沒事
I'm fine.
我...
I'm...
我沒事
I'm fine.
我人生中 只有幾個醍醐灌頂的瞬間
A few times in my life I've had moments of absolute clarity.
那短暫的瞬間裡...
When for a few brief seconds...
...寂靜淹沒了嘈雜...
...the silence drowns out the noise...
...我更能夠感覺 而不是思考
...and I can feel rather than think.
一切都顯得那麼明晰...
And things seem so sharp...
世界都顯得那麼清澈...
And the world seems so fresh...
...彷彿一切都物歸原主了
...as though it had all just come into existence.
但我永遠無法維持這樣的瞬間
I can never make these moments last.
我牢牢抓住它們...
I cling to them...
...但如同萬事萬物 它們都消逝了
...but like everything they fade.
我一直活在這幾個時刻當中
I've lived my live on these moments.
但它們又將我推回當下...
They pull me back to the present...
然後我意識到
...and I realize that
一切都是按照命中注定的軌道行駛
everything is exactly the way it was meant to be.
就這樣 襲來
And just like that it came.
破爛熊字幕組
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
歡迎加入